CHUCK R. FIELDS

1493 N Hampton Ct • Greenfield, IN 46140

317-491-3419 • chuckrfields@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/chuckfields/

SUMMARY

Chuck is a veteran of the information technology industry, with 20+ years experience developing & managing robust web applications as a dev team leader, full-stack developer, relational database architect, report developer and consultant. Before that Chuck was a marketing director helping businesses both nationally and internationally, so he understands how to apply technology to improve business.

His skill set includes back-end development (LAMP, WAMP, MERN and WISA stacks), as well as front-end development with frameworks/libraries including Bootstrap, jQuery, React, JavaScript and many others. He founded one of the first CRM web sites for the financial industry in the late 1990s (recognized by American Banker), and has been in the industry ever since.

He holds a Bachelor's Degree in Communications, which helps him translate technical terms with enthusiasm while ensuring understanding. He's also an award-winning podcast host & producer, with an audience in all 50 U.S. states and 161 countries.

I/T VIDEO CLIPS

What is Agile methodology? | Benefits of Rapid Application Development (methodology) | Why Chuck loves to solve problems!

SKILLS

HTML, CSS, Responsive Design, JavaScript, jQuery, AJAX, ASP.NET, C#, VB.net, SQL

EDUCATION

Indiana University - B.A. Communications (1991)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Adjunct Instructor at Butler University Coding Bootcamp, Indianapolis, IN

11/2020-Present

• Teach students HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Express.js, React.js, Node.js, progressive web apps, agile methodology, computer science, MongoDB, MySQL, Git, and more.

Consultant, SpaceTech Corporation, Indianapolis, IN

1/2006-Present

- Developed secure web application to reduce client staff time by 30% by automating processes Role: Lead developer & DB
 architect WISA stack. Language: vb.net; .NET Framework 4.7, MSSQL, HTML 5, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, RESTful
 API, SOAP, GIT
- Created & integrated eCommerce solution, saving client 25% (thousands of dollars per month) in payment fees while reducing processing time (from hours to minutes) Role: Lead developer & DB architect WISA stack. Language: C#, .NET Framework 4.5, MSSQL, HTML 5, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, RESTful API, SOAP, GIT
- Created web application, facilitating vendor data completion through secure form submission, integrated with back-end SQL Server 2016 database Role: Lead developer & DB architect WISA stack. Language: C#, MVC, .NET Framework 4.5,
 MSSQL, HTML 5, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, RESTful API, SOAP, GIT
- Rewrote legacy FoxPro application Role: Lead developer & DB architect WISA stack. Language: C#, .NET Framework 4.7,
 MSSQL, SSRS, HTML 5, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, GIT
- Created 100+ reports using SSRS for government entity, including improved speed through SQL Server normalization, eliminating cursors, etc. – WISA stack
- Created and launched several eCommerce web sites for clients built on PHP, JavaScript, MySQL LAMP/WAMP stacks

- Secured several PHP sites that had been hacked before client approached me to resolve, upgrade and maintain LAMP stack
- Implemented several CMS (Content Management Systems) for clients including DNN (with custom modules) and WordPress WAMP stack
- Created machine learning apps using Python and MongoDB, as well as single-page applications with React. MERN stack
- Converted several client methodologies from waterfall to Agile & RAD

Application Developer for C. P. Morgan, Indianapolis, IN

10/2003-9/2005

- Converted company website from ASP to ASP.NET, storing and capturing user data in MSSQL database and creating userfriendly content management system with secure (SSL) login. Increased unique visitor traffic an average of 40% monthly
- Developed an innovative paperless contract VB.NET application, reducing errors and turnaround time by integrating client and sales data in MSSQL database and routing electronic contract for approval. Populated contracts using XML data and XSD schemas, and file replication. Captured hard-copy contracts as electronic files via Digital Senders and stored in SharePoint. Deployed new releases monthly to more than 30 sales offices across the U.S.
- Started as independent consultant then hired on as full-time developer

Web Solutions Manager for Netisun, LLC, Indianapolis, IN

1/2001-3/2002

- Launched and led web development division for the company, achieving 300% increase in web development revenue, earning "Million Dollar Award" from Indiana Information Technology Association (INITA)
- Developed and project managed more than 100 web sites with a team of 4 developers. Stacks: LAMP (with Perl), WISA
- Backend work included MSSQL database integration, cross-platform/cross-browser coding, user data capture, e-commerce applications (Able Commerce and Miva Merchant), creation of ASP content management modules, online surveys, instant graphical reporting, along with front-end web design.
- Most notable success included rapid (three-week) development of ASP e-commerce and content management for non-profit's web site, increasing client's potential to raise contributions while reducing management time.

Web Content Manager & Developer for LUCRUM, Inc., Indianapolis, IN

2/2000-12/2000

- Project manager and lead editor for the company's content-focused eBusiness web site. Front-end work included ASP page
 design and weekly streaming radio program while backend work included MSSQL database.
- Increased number of opt-in registrations from 200 to 16,000 during tenure. Achieved 400% increase in number of sales leads through aggressive web-based marketing. Leads accounted directly for more than \$400,000 of annual revenue. Reduced web development costs by 70% by developing site in-house.
- Won 2nd Place for most innovative web site in INC Magazine Web Awards

Marketing Specialist & Webmaster for Centillion Digital Systems, Inc., Indianapolis, IN

11/1998-2/2000

- Developed and implemented three corporate ASP web sites: U.S., Sweden and Germany. Mainly front-end work, focusing on web site design. Also developed lead generation system, increasing web site leads by 40%.
- Other responsibilities included the creation of marketing brochures, flyers, and technical manuals as well as multimedia sales presentations and proposals.

HOBBIES/INTERESTS

In addition to artificial intelligence, machine learning, Python, .NET and a huge interest in space exploration, I also host and produce two highly successful, award-winning podcasts with audiences in 157 countries and all 50 U.S. states:

OnlineCoffeeBreak.com

An entertainment interview series featuring celebrities & musicians including Zoe Perry ('Young Sheldon'), The Go-Go's, Air Supply, Earth, Wind & Fire, Queen's Brian May & more.

- 2020, 2019 People's Choice Podcast Awards nominee (Entertainment)
- Runner up 2020 Indy PopCon Podcast Awards (TV/Film)

YourSpaceJourney.com

A series featuring interviews with leaders in space exploration, including NASA Administrator Jim Bridenstine (conducted at NASA HQ), RocketLab Founder Peter Beck, ULA CEO Tory Bruno, plus a unique "around the world in space" series featuring worldwide space programs such as ESA, JAXA, UAE & more. Also includes onsite coverage of several rocket launches.

- 2020 People's Choice Podcast Awards nominee (Science)
- Winner 2020 Indy PopCon Podcast Awards (Science)